Preliminary Guide to the Webb Family Papers circa 1918-1980s
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Preliminary Guide to the Webb Family Papers
circa 1918-1980s
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
MSSM.069
Webb famliy
44.42 Linear feet of shelf space 41 Boxes
This collection consists of the papers of the Webb family of Pullman, Washington, mostly related to Everett M. Webb and Louise Ott Webb, with a small amount related to their children, Elizabeth, Richard, and Dorothy.
Everett M. Webb (1898-1972) and Louise Ott Webb (1902-1981) were both members of the Class of 1924 at Washington State College. Louise earned a Secretarial Training certificate (1922), and Everett earned a Bachelor of Science in Agriculture (1924) and a Master of Arts in Education (1941). Everett Webb was a member of the faculty at Washington State University from 1936 until his retirement in 1964, serving as State Supervisor of Vocational Agriculture and Education. Everett served as a faculty advisor for the Tau Kappa Epsilon fraternity (TKE), and worked closely with the Future Farmers of America (FFA) and 4-H Clubs in Washington State. Louise served as the local chapter advisor for the Kappa Kappa Gamma sorority (KKG). Both Webbs were very active in the American Legion and in many civic and community organizations.
In 1971, their children, Richard E. Webb, Elizabeth Webb Clark, and Dorothy Webb Loan, established the Everett M. and Louise Ott Webb Scholarship at WSU for undergraduate students majoring in agricultural education.
This collection consists of the papers of the Webb family of Pullman, Washington, mostly related to Everett M. Webb and Louise Ott Webb, with a small amount related to their children, Elizabeth, Richard, and Dorothy. Everett Webb's papers include office files from his career at Washington State University (WSU), and material related to his work with the Future Farmers of America (FFA), the Tau Kappa Epsilon fraternity (TKE), and his involvement with the American Legion. Louise Ott Webb's papers include records related to the Kappa Kappa Gamma sorority (KKG) and her involvement with the American Legion Auxiliary. The collection contains correspondence, minutes, ephemera, newspaper clippings, reports, photographs, and financial records.
This is an unprocessed collection. Arrangement reflects either pre-existing order from the records’ creator or preliminary sorting performed by staff.
This collection is open and available for research use, except for ritual or private materials (if present) related to the Tau Kappa Epsilon fraternity. If found, the repository has agreed to remove such materials from the collection.
This collection was donated to the Washington State University Libraries in multiple installments by the Webb family and Mrs. Benton M. (Barbara) Collins in 1982 (MS.1982.38, MS.1982.55, and Richard Old in 2008 (MS.2008.04).
American Legion Maynard-Price Post of Pullman #52 Records, 1920-1978 (Cage 514)
American Legion Maynard-Price Post of Pullman #52 Records, circa 1919-1980 (MS 1986.06)
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Webb, Everett M., 1898-1972 -- Archives; Webb, Louise O., 1902-1981 -- Archives; Webb, Everett M., 1898-1972; Webb, Louise O., 1902-1981
Webb family -- Archives
Tau Kappa Epsilon; Washington State University -- Faculty -- Archives; American Legion. Maynard-Price Post No. 52 (Pullman, Wash.); Kappa Kappa Gamma
Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- History -- Sources
Agriculture; Washington (State)
- Future Farmers of America (FFA)
  - Vocational agriculture, 1950s-1970s (Box 1)
  - 4H club materials, 1940s (Box 1)
  - State Future Farmers of America (FFA) Convention agendas, circa 1950s (Box 1)
  - Leadership Training Program for State Association of the FFA (Box 1)
  - Assorted correspondence, brochures, and newspaper clipping (Box 1)
- FFA/vocational agriculture
  - Class notes, rosters, and outlines for Education 72 class, 1950-1951 (Box 2)
  - Summer short course materials, 1941, 1945-1946 (Box 2)
  - Washington State College memos, 1950s (Box 2)
  - Careers in Agriculture Committee, 1958-1959 (Box 2)
  - Agriculture Curriculum Committee, 1957-1962 (Box 2)
  - Committee on Instruction, 1956-1958 (Box 2)
  - Agricultural census (Box 2)
  - State Board of Vocational Agriculture (Box 2)
  - FFA correspondence, photos, brochures, income books, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 2)
  - Junior Livestock Show programs, 1930s-1960s (Box 2)
  - FFA annual reports and National Convention proceedings, 1950s-1960s (Box 2)
  - Correspondence to Everett Webb, vocational agriculture instructor supervisor, 1960s (Box 3)
  - FFA programs and judging cards, 1960s (Box 3)
  - Vocational agriculture photos, circa 1950s (Box 3)
  - Vocational and technical school information (Box 3)
  - Washington Purebred Dairy Cattle Association Judging Conference program (Box 3)
  - Washington Junior Poultry Exposition program, 1960s (Box 3)
  - Communication through Radio and TV notes and agendas (Box 3)
  - Workshop of State Supervisors of Vocational Agriculture reports, 1960s (Box 3)
  - WSU Curriculum Advisory Program, policies and procedures (Box 3)
  - Exam questions and bibliographies (Box 3)
  - Education 172, 1938 (Box 3)
  - Class papers FFA National Radio Program reports (Box 3)
  - FFA musical score (Box 3)
  - Education 101 and agriculture articles (Box 3)
- Vocational agriculture, high schools, 1920s-1930s
  - Vocational agriculture photos, class activities, project outlines, yearbooks (Box 4)
  - Nesika, Washington, Dayton High School materials, 1920s-1930s (Box 4)
  - Judging recommendations – poultry (Box 4)
  - Agricultural Conference and Summer School programs (Box 4)
  - Agriculture, 1920s-1930s (Box 4)
- Vocational agriculture conferences
  - Box of name badges, undated (Box 5)
  - Agriculture Wives Conference, 1944-1963 (Box 5)
  - Newspaper clippings and programs for FFA (Box 5)
  - Programs for Pacific Northwest Vocational Agricultural Research Council, 1950s-1970s (Box 5)
  - American Association of Teacher Educators in Agriculture, 1960s-1970s (Box 5)
  - Annual Pacific Regional Conference for Vocational Education in Agriculture, 1964 (Box 5)
- Vocational agriculture at Washington State University
  - Stormfront News, 1927 (Box 6)
  - Photos, circa 1950s (Box 6)
  - Federal Security Agency circulars regarding vocational training, 1940s (Box 6)
  - Student manuals and reports, 1940s-1960s (Box 6)
  - Washington State Board for Vocational Education reports, 1960s (Box 6)
  - Agriculture education newsletters, 1950s-1960s (Box 6)
  - Evaluation criteria for AH Webb’s courses, 1950s (Box 6)
  - Correspondence to Webb as agriculture education instructor, 1940s-1960s (Box 7)
  - Conference programs and miscellaneous agriculture newsletters, 1960s (Box 7)
  - Board for Vocational Education expense records, 1942-1948 (Box 8)
  - Class notes, 1940s (Box 8)
  - Unidentified photos, circa 1920s-1940s (Box 8)
  - Washington State College memos, 1960s (Box 8)
  - Washington State College memos, 1960s (Box 9)
- Vocational agriculture
  - Republican County Central Committee report (Box 10)
  - Pullman Chamber of Commerce report, 1950s (Box 10)
  - Junior Livestock Show photos, 1960 (Box 10)
  - Vocational agriculture brochures and newsletters, circa 1960s (Box 10)
  - College of Agriculture Teacher Conference materials, 1960s (Box 10)
  - State Board for Vocational Agriculture materials, circa 1960s (Box 10)
  - Supervisory reports, 1950s (Box 10)
  - Vocational Agriculture Supervisory Staff Meeting, 1970s (Box 12)
  - Animal sciences text manuscript, 1949 (Box 12)
  - Columbia Basin Project reports, 1940s (Box 12)
  - WA State Board for Vocational Agriculture, 1950s (Box 12)
  - WA Interscholastic Activities Association, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 12)
  - Vocational Agriculture Supervisory Staff Meeting, 1960s (Box 13)
  - Webb correspondence, 1950s (Box 13)
  - Vocational agriculture materials, 1940s-1950s (Box 13)
  - Conferences, 1940s-1950s (Box 13)
  - Agricultural Scholarship Committee, 1960s (Box 15)
  - Course materials, circa 1960s (Box 15)
  - FFA constitutions, 1930s-1940s (Box 15)
  - Pacific Regional Conferences of Farm Mechanics, 1950s (Box 15)
  - Agricultural Supervisors Meeting, 1950s (Box 15)
  - Conferences, 1950s (Box 15)
  - Scholarship materials, 1940s-1950s (Box 15)
  - Course materials, 1940s-1950s (Box 15)
  - Teaching manuals, reports, and newsletters (Box 16)
  - High school vocational agriculture reports, 1950s (Box 16)
  - State guidance for agricultural education, 1950s (Box 16)
  - State Board for Vocational Agriculture, correspondence, 1950s (Box 16)
  - Course materials, 1950s (Box 16)
- Vocational agriculture/correspondence
  - Washington State College course materials, 1950s-1960s (Box 11)
  - Washington State College meeting minutes/documents (Box 11)
  - Webb correspondence, circa 1940s (Box 11)
- Vocational agriculture meetings
  - State Staff Meeting, 1950s-1960s (Box 14)
  - National FFA Convention, 1950s-1960s (Box 14)
  - NW Agriculture Teacher Training Conference, 1950s-1960s (Box 14)
- Vocational agriculture and Washington State College work
  - Vocational agriculture reports, 1950s (Box 17)
  - Fraternity Welfare Committee, 1960s (Box 17)
  - Training Supervisors of Farm Laborers course (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous course materials (Box 17)
- Kappa Kappa Gamma (KKG)
  - Gamma Eta Society of Kappa Kappa Gamma finances ledger, 1940s (Box 18)
  - KKG correspondence and rosters, 1950s-1960s (Box 18)
  - Committees, bylaws, KKG history, standing rules, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 19)
  - Reports (treasurers, annual) (Box 19)
  - Guidance documents (Box 19)
  - Brochures (Box 19)
  - Event invitations/souvenirs (Box 19)
  - Yearbooks, 1950s, 1980s (Box 19)
  - Correspondence with Louise Webb (Box 19)
  - Photos and KKG histories, circa 1960s (Box 20)
- Kappa Kappa Gamma publications
  - The Key, 1920-1950 (Box 21)
  - The Key, 1951-1971 (Box 22)
  - The Key, 1972-1977 (Box 23)
  - Notes, bylaws, newsletters, club history, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 23)
- Tau Kappa Epsilon (TKE)
  - TKE correspondence, finances, newsletters, reports, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 24)
  - TEKE Holding Company minutes, 1930s (Box 25)
  - TKE ritual, philosophy, constitution, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 25)
  - Correspondence, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 25)
  - TKE reports, minutes, notes (Box 25)
  - TKE annual reports, 1929-1940 (Box 26)
  - TEKE Guide, 1954 (Box 26)
  - Calendars, correspondence, conclave schedules, 1950s-1960s (Box 26)
  - Titles, newsletters, financial reports, songs, committee reports, 1950s-1960s (Box 26)
  - Correspondence, financial reports, newsletters (Box 27)
  - Phi Delta Kappa newsletters, 1940s-1970s (Box 27)
  - TKE newsletters, 1930s-1960s (Box 27)
- American Legion
  - American Legion programs, constitutions, brochures, 1960s-1970s (Box 28)
  - Reports, rosters, newsletters, notes, proceedings, 1960s-1970s (Box 28)
  - Pins, ribbons, conference IDs, circa 1960s (Box 28)
  - Certificates, newspaper clippings, photos, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 29)
  - Correspondence, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 29)
  - Pins, ID badges, circa 1960s (Box 29)
  - Newsletters, programs, agendas, brochures, correspondence, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 30)
  - Correspondence, reports, programs, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 31)
- American Legion/American Legion Auxiliary
  - American Legion events, booklets, memos, and convention materials, 1950s (Box 32)
  - American Legion Auxiliary programs, newspaper clippings, officer lists, correspondence, reports, 1960s (Box 32)
  - American Legion newspaper clippings, circa 1960s (Box 32)
  - American Legion Auxiliary National News (newsletters), 1960s-1970s (Box 32)
  - American Legion/American Legion Auxiliary (Box Box 33:)
  - Convention materials, 1970s (Box 33)
  - Auxiliary correspondence with Mrs. Webb, 1940s (Box 33)
  - Auxiliary speech guide, programs, newspaper clippings, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 33)
  - Auxiliary convention materials, newspaper clippings, reports, notes, 1960s-1970s (Box 34)
  - American Legion notes and programs, 1960s-1970s (Box 34)
  - Unsorted notes, publications, convention materials, correspondence, circa 1960s (Box 35)
- Unsorted correspondence and finances
  - Letters, documents, ledgers, thesis, circa 1960s (Box 36)
- Everett biography, correspondence and finances
  - Fairfield Farm ledger, Everett Webb biographical notes, and thesis. (Box 37)
- Community work (church, YMCA)
  - Bulletins and programs, Presbyterian Church of Pullman, circa 1960s (Box 38)
  - Greystone Church records, 1940s-1970s (Box 38)
  - Presbyterian Church Circle and Women’s Association, 1960s-1970s (Box 38)
  - YWCA, circa 1960s (Box 38)
- Oversized materials
  - Agricultural education (Box 39)
  - Greystone Church (Box 39)
  - State Board of Vocational Education, circa 1940s (Box 39)
  - Newsletters: The Young Citizens, 1940s (Box 40)
  - Supplemental charter, Legion Post 52, May 1958 (Box 41)
  - Oversized photos (Box Oversized)
  - Oversized: National FFA Convention (Box Oversized)
  - Oversized: series of enlarged images for Soil Conservation Service (16x20 inches) (Box Oversized)
    Shows fields under cultivation, equipment and techniques, and evidence of erosion. A few of the photos have narrative captions, but most have only reference numbers.